<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marine Resources -Oil and Gas on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marine Resources -Oil and Gas on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General Idea of Drilling</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/drilling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/drilling/</guid>
      <description>Drilling for oil and gas in marine environments is a complex and challenging process. It involves the construction of offshore drilling rigs or platforms, the use of specialized equipment and tools, and the implementation of strict safety and environmental protection measures.
General idea on drilling The first step in drilling for marine resources is to identify a potential drilling location. This is done using a variety of methods, including seismic surveys and geological studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipe Laying including use of Submersibles</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/pipelay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/pipelay/</guid>
      <description>Definition: Pipe laying is the process of installing pipelines on the seabed or underground. Submersibles are vehicles that can operate underwater. They are used in a variety of tasks, including pipe laying.
Types of submersibles used in pipe laying There are two main types of submersibles used in pipe laying:
Remotely operated vehicles (ROVs): ROVs are unmanned submersibles that are controlled from a surface vessel. They are typically used for tasks such as inspection, maintenance, and repair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Facilities</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/storage/</guid>
      <description>There are a variety of storage facilities used for oil and gas, depending on the type of product being stored and the location. Some of the most common types of storage facilities include:
Above-ground tanks: Above-ground tanks are the most common type of storage tank for oil and gas. They can be made of steel, concrete, or fiberglass, and come in a variety of sizes and shapes. Above-ground tanks are typically used for storing crude oil, refined petroleum products, and natural gas liquids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Drilling Rigs, Drill Ships and Well head Oroduction Platforms</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/typesofships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/typesofships/</guid>
      <description>Types of Drilling Rigs Land rigs: Land rigs are the most common type of drilling rig, and can be used to drill wells in a variety of locations, including deserts, forests, and mountains.
Drilling barges: Drilling barges are used to drill wells in shallow water, typically less than 300 feet deep.
Jack-up rigs: Jack-up rigs are used to drill wells in water depths of up to 400 feet. They have legs that can be raised or lowered to elevate the rig above the waterline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Terminals</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/terminaltypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/terminaltypes/</guid>
      <description>There are three main types of sea terminals:
General cargo terminals: These terminals handle a variety of types of cargo, including break-bulk cargo (such as machinery and vehicles), neo-bulk cargo (such as grain and forest products), and containerized cargo.
Bulk cargo terminals: These terminals handle bulk cargo, such as coal, grain, iron ore, and oil. Bulk cargo terminals are typically specialized to handle a specific type of cargo.
Passenger terminals: These terminals handle passenger traffic, such as ferries and cruise ships.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
