<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marine Resources- Minerals on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marine Resources- Minerals on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desalination processes</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/desalination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/desalination/</guid>
      <description>There are two main types of desalination processes: thermal and membrane. Thermal desalination processes use heat to evaporate seawater, leaving behind the salt and impurities. The most common thermal desalination processes are:
Multi-stage flash distillation (MSF): MSF is the most mature thermal desalination technology. In MSF, seawater is heated to a high temperature and then flashed into steam. The steam is then condensed to produce fresh water.
Multiple-effect distillation (MED): MED is similar to MSF, but it uses a series of chambers with different temperatures and pressures to improve efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraction of Minerals from seabed</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralextraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralextraction/</guid>
      <description>Definition The extraction of minerals from the seabed is a relatively new and developing industry. It involves the retrieval of mineral deposits from the ocean floor at depths of 200 metres /660 feet or more.
There are three main types of mineral deposits that are of interest for seabed mining: polymetallic nodules, seafloor massive sulfides (SMS), and cobalt-rich ferromanganese crusts.
Polymetallic nodules are potato-sized rocks that are found on the deep ocean floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods of extracting minerals from seawater</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralsextract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralsextract/</guid>
      <description>Methods of extraction of Minerals There are a number of methods of extracting minerals from seawater. Some of the most common methods include:
Solar evaporation: This is the oldest and simplest method of extracting minerals from seawater. It involves using the sun&amp;rsquo;s heat to evaporate seawater, leaving behind the mineral salts. Solar evaporation is typically used to extract salt from seawater, but it can also be used to extract other minerals, such as magnesium and potassium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand and Gravel Dredging</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/sandgrvldredge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/sandgrvldredge/</guid>
      <description>Definition Sand and gravel dredging is the process of extracting sand and gravel from the bottom of rivers, lakes, oceans, and other bodies of water. It is a common method of obtaining these materials, which are used in a variety of construction and industrial applications.
There are two main types of sand and gravel dredging: Hydraulic dredging: This type of dredging uses a pump to suck up sand and gravel from the bottom of the water body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seabed Sampling</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seabedsample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seabedsample/</guid>
      <description>Definition Seabed sampling is the process of collecting sediment and rock samples from the ocean floor.
Seabed samples are collected for a variety of purposes, including: To study the composition and distribution of seabed sediments: This information can be used to understand the geological history of an area, as well as to identify potential resources, such as minerals and oil and gas.
To monitor the environmental health of the ocean: Seabed samples can be analyzed for contaminants, such as heavy metals and pesticides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seismic and Sonar Profiling</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seismicsonarprofiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seismicsonarprofiling/</guid>
      <description>Definition Seismic and sonar profiling are two types of geophysical surveying techniques that are used to image the subsurface of the Earth.
Functioning Seismic profiling uses sound waves to generate images of the subsurface. Seismic waves are generated by a source, such as an explosive charge or a vibroseis truck, and they travel through the subsurface at different speeds depending on the density and elasticity of the rocks they encounter. The waves are reflected back to the surface by different layers of rock, and these reflections are detected by receivers, such as geophones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
