<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fishing on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fishing on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conservation of resources</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/conserv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/conserv/</guid>
      <description>What is Conservation of Marine Resources Conservation of marine resources is the protection and preservation of ecosystems in oceans and seas through planned management in order to prevent the over-exploitation of these marine resources.
There are a number of different ways to conserve marine resources, including: Marine protected areas (MPAs): MPAs are areas of the ocean where certain activities, such as fishing or mining, are restricted or prohibited. MPAs can help to protect marine ecosystems and the species that live in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demersal and Pelagic fishing</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/demerpelag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/demerpelag/</guid>
      <description>Demersal and pelagic fishing are two different types of fishing that target different types of fish in different habitats.
Demersal fishing is the fishing of fish that live on or near the bottom of the ocean. These fish are also known as groundfish. Demersal fish are typically caught using bottom trawls, gillnets, and longlines.Some examples of demersal fish include cod, haddock, flounder, sole, and shrimp.
Pelagic fishing is the fishing of fish that live in the open ocean, away from the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Types</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishtyp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishtyp/</guid>
      <description>Fish Types Types of fish marine resources can be classified according to their body type, habitat, or commercial value.
According to body type: Bony fish: This is the largest group of fish, accounting for over 95% of all fish species. They have a skeleton made of bone and a swim bladder that helps them control their buoyancy. Examples of bony fish include tuna, cod, salmon, and herring.
Cartilaginous fish: This group includes sharks, rays, and skates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fishing Factory Vessels</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfactory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfactory/</guid>
      <description>What are Fishing Factory Vessels? Fishing factory vessels (FFVs) are large ocean-going ships that are equipped to catch, process, and store fish. They are also known as fish processing vessels, mother ships, or floating factories. FFVs are typically used to fish in remote waters, where they can stay at sea for months at a time.
FFVs are highly efficient fishing vessels that can catch and process large quantities of fish. They are also equipped with sophisticated freezing and storage facilities, which allow them to maintain the freshness of the fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographical location of fishing grounds</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishgrnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishgrnd/</guid>
      <description>What are fishing grounds? Fishing grounds are areas of the ocean where fish are abundant and can be caught commercially. They are typically located in areas where there is a lot of food for fish, such as near continental shelves, upwelling areas, and around coral reefs.
The geographical location of fishing grounds varies depending on the type of fish being targeted. For example, tuna fishing grounds are typically located in tropical and subtropical waters, while cod fishing grounds are typically located in colder waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine Fish Farming</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfarm/</guid>
      <description>What is Marine Fish farming? Marine fish farming is the cultivation of marine fish in enclosed areas, such as coastal waters, offshore cages, or tanks. It is a rapidly growing industry, as it offers a number of advantages over wild fishing, including:
Sustainability: Marine fish farming can help to reduce the pressure on wild fish populations. This is because farmed fish are raised in controlled environments, where they are less susceptible to overfishing and other stressors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
