<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ocean Governance on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ocean Governance on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Areas Beyond National Jurisdiction</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/abnj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/abnj/</guid>
      <description>What is ABNJ? Areas beyond national jurisdiction (ABNJ) are those parts of the ocean that are not under the control of any one country. They cover about 64% of the ocean&amp;rsquo;s surface and 95% of its volume, making them the largest global commons on Earth.
ABNJ are home to a wide range of marine life and ecosystems, including many that are unique and found nowhere else on the planet. They also play a vital role in regulating the climate and providing essential resources to people around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commission on Limits of the Continental Shelf</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/clcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/clcs/</guid>
      <description>What is CLCS and describe it&amp;rsquo;s functions. The Commission on the Limits of the Continental Shelf (CLCS) is a 21-member body of experts established under the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) to consider submissions from coastal states on the outer limits of their continental shelf beyond 200 nautical miles from their baselines.
The CLCS&amp;rsquo;s work is important because the continental shelf is a valuable resource that can contain oil, gas, and other minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries(CCRF)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/ccrf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/ccrf/</guid>
      <description>What is CCRF? The FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries (CCRF) is a voluntary international instrument that sets out principles and standards for the conservation, management and development of living aquatic resources. It was adopted by the FAO Conference in 1995 and has since been endorsed by over 180 countries.
The CCRF is based on the following principles: The precautionary approach: States should act with caution when taking decisions that could have a negative impact on living aquatic resources, even if there is no scientific certainty that such an impact will occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Seabed Authority</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/isa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/isa/</guid>
      <description>T## he International Seabed Authority (ISA):
is an intergovernmental organization of 167 member states and the European Union established under the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) and its 1994 Agreement on Implementation. The ISA is headquartered in Kingston, Jamaica.
The ISA&amp;rsquo;s dual mission is to: Organize and control mining activities in the international seabed, which is considered the &amp;ldquo;common heritage of mankind.&amp;rdquo; Protect the marine environment from potential harm caused by mining activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Governance</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/defoceangov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/defoceangov/</guid>
      <description>What is Ocean Governance? Ocean governance is the process by which the world&amp;rsquo;s oceans are managed and used. It encompasses a wide range of actors and institutions, including governments, international organizations, businesses, civil society groups, and individuals.
Ocean governance is important because the oceans play a vital role in the global economy and environment. They provide food, jobs, transportation, and recreation. They also regulate the climate, produce oxygen, and support a wide range of biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Development</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/sdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/sdev/</guid>
      <description>Marine sustainable development is the management and use of marine resources in a way that meets the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs. It is essential to ensure that the oceans remain healthy and productive, and that the benefits of marine resources are shared equitably.
There are many different aspects of marine sustainable development, including:
Sustainable fisheries: Fisheries management that ensures that fish stocks are harvested at a sustainable rate, and that fishing practices do not harm the marine environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNFSA</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/unfsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/unfsa/</guid>
      <description>What is UNFSA? The United Nations Agreement on the Conservation and Management of Straddling Fish Stocks and Highly Migratory Fish Stocks (UNFSA) is an international agreement that aims to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of straddling fish stocks and highly migratory fish stocks.
Straddling fish stocks are those that occur both within the exclusive economic zones (EEZs) of coastal states and in the high seas. Highly migratory fish stocks are those that migrate across the EEZs of two or more coastal states or extend into the high seas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
