<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study for Extra Master on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Study for Extra Master on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agenda 21 UNFCCC </title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/agenda_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/agenda_21/</guid>
      <description>Agenda 21 is a comprehensive plan of action to achieve sustainable development. It was adopted by 178 governments at the United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED) in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, in 1992. Agenda 21 is a non-binding document, but it has been influential in guiding sustainable development efforts around the world.
Agenda 21 covers a wide range of issues, including:
Sustainable agriculture and rural development Conservation of biological diversity Combating deforestation Protecting the atmosphere Managing fragile ecosystems Promoting sustainable energy use Managing hazardous wastes Promoting sustainable human settlements Agenda 21 also emphasizes the importance of international cooperation and participation of all stakeholders in achieving sustainable development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto Protocol-UNFCCC (UNFCCC,Kyoto,1997)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/kyotoproto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/kyotoproto/</guid>
      <description>The Kyoto Protocol is an international treaty that was adopted in 1997 at the Third Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) in Kyoto, Japan. It entered into force in 2005 and has been ratified by 192 countries, including India.
The Kyoto Protocol is the first international treaty to set binding targets for the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions. It commits developed countries to reduce their emissions by an average of 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional Seas Programme (RSP,Paris,2015)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/rsparis2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/rsparis2015/</guid>
      <description>The Regional Seas Programme (RSP) is a global partnership of 14 Regional Seas Conventions and Action Plans (RSCAPs) that work to protect and manage the marine and coastal environment. The RSP is coordinated by the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP) and is funded by a variety of sources, including governments, international organizations, and the private sector.
The RSP was launched in 1974 at the United Nations Conference on the Human Environment in Stockholm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2002 World Summit on Sustainable Development-Rio&#43;10 (WSSD,Johannesburg,2002)The 2012 United Nations Conference on Sustainable Development-Rio&#43;20 (UNCSD,Rio,2012)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/rio&#43;10_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/rio&#43;10_20/</guid>
      <description>##Rio+10
The 2002 World Summit on Sustainable Development (WSSD), also known as Rio+10, was held in Johannesburg, South Africa, from 26 August to 4 September 2002. It was a follow-up to the 1992 Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.
The Rio+10 Summit was attended by over 100 heads of state and government, as well as representatives from civil society and the private sector. It focused on the implementation of the outcomes of the 1992 Earth Summit, and on identifying new challenges and opportunities for sustainable development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commission on Sustainable Development (CSD,Rio,1992)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/csd1992/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/csd1992/</guid>
      <description>The Commission on Sustainable Development (CSD) was a functional commission of the United Nations Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC) that was established in 1992 following the Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro. The CSD was tasked with reviewing the implementation of Agenda 21, the global plan for sustainable development that was adopted at the Earth Summit.
The Global Environment Facility (GEF) is an international financial institution that was established in 1992 to provide &amp;gt;funding for projects that address global environmental problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intergovernmental Conference on biological diversity beyond national jurisdiction (BBNJ,2023)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/bbnj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/bbnj/</guid>
      <description>The Intergovernmental Conference on biological diversity beyond national jurisdiction (BBNJ) concluded on June 19, 2023, with the adoption of a landmark agreement to conserve and sustainably use marine biodiversity in areas beyond national jurisdiction (ABNJ). The agreement, which was adopted by consensus by the 193 member states of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), is the first comprehensive international treaty to address marine biodiversity in ABNJ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The London Convention on the Prevention of Marine Pollution by Dumping of Wastes and Other Matter (LC 1972)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/londondump1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/londondump1972/</guid>
      <description>The London Convention on the Prevention of Marine Pollution by Dumping of Wastes and Other Matter (LC 1972) is a global treaty adopted in 1972 to protect the marine environment from human activities, including the dumping of wastes. The Convention entered into force in 1975 and currently has 87 Contracting Parties.
The London Convention prohibits the dumping of certain hazardous materials, such as organohalogen compounds, mercury, cadmium, persistent plastics, and radioactive wastes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED),1992</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unced/</guid>
      <description>The United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED), also known as the Earth Summit, was a major United Nations conference held in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, from June 3 to 14, 1992. It was the largest gathering of world leaders as of 1992, with 117 heads of state and representatives of 178 nations in all attending.
The Earth Summit was convened in recognition of the growing interdependence of the environment and development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD,Rio,1992) </title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unconvbiodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unconvbiodiversity/</guid>
      <description>The United Nations Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) is an international treaty that aims to promote sustainable development. It was adopted at the Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro in 1992 and has been ratified by 196 countries, including India.
The CBD has three main objectives:
The conservation of biological diversity. The sustainable use of its components. The fair and equitable sharing of the benefits arising from the use of genetic resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC,Rio,1992)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unfccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unfccc/</guid>
      <description>The United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is an international treaty that was adopted in 1992 at the Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. It entered into force in 1994 and has been ratified by 198 countries, including India.
The UNFCCC is a landmark agreement that sets out the global framework for addressing climate change. It recognizes that climate change is a common concern of humankind and that all countries have a responsibility to address it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Nations Convention on Human Environment,1972</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unhe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unhe/</guid>
      <description>The United Nations Conference on the Human Environment, also known as the Stockholm Conference, was held in Stockholm, Sweden, from June 5-16, 1972. It was the first major international conference to address environmental issues.
The conference was attended by representatives from 113 countries, and resulted in the adoption of the Stockholm Declaration, an Action Plan for the Human Environment, and several resolutions.
The Stockholm Declaration is a landmark document in environmental law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Nations Environment Programme</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unepcont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unepcont/</guid>
      <description> Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; / [pdf] View the PDF file here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/typoftides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/typoftides/</guid>
      <description>Tides can be classified in a number of ways, including by frequency, range, and type.
Frequency Tides can be classified by frequency based on the number of high and low tides that occur each day. The three main types of tidal frequencies are:
Diurnal tides: One high tide and one low tide per day. Semi-diurnal tides: Two high tides and two low tides per day. Mixed tides: A combination of diurnal and semi-diurnal tides, with the number of high and low tides varying per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/about/</guid>
      <description>Right now we are not concentrating on parts A and B . we are focussing on C only Just Study</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active geological processes</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/actgeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/actgeo/</guid>
      <description>What are Active Geological processes? Active geological processes are the forces that are constantly shaping and changing the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. These processes can be slow and gradual, like erosion, or they can be sudden and catastrophic, like volcanic eruptions and earthquakes.
Here are some examples of active geological processes: Volcanoes Volcanoes are openings in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust that allow molten rock, ash, and gases to escape. When a volcano erupts, it can release a tremendous amount of energy, causing widespread destruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Areas Beyond National Jurisdiction</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/abnj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/abnj/</guid>
      <description>What is ABNJ? Areas beyond national jurisdiction (ABNJ) are those parts of the ocean that are not under the control of any one country. They cover about 64% of the ocean&amp;rsquo;s surface and 95% of its volume, making them the largest global commons on Earth.
ABNJ are home to a wide range of marine life and ecosystems, including many that are unique and found nowhere else on the planet. They also play a vital role in regulating the climate and providing essential resources to people around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic techniques of Hydrographic Surveying</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/bashydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/bashydro/</guid>
      <description>Hydrographic surveying is a complex and demanding field, but it is also essential for safe navigation and maritime transportation. Hydrographic surveyors use a variety of techniques to collect data about the depth and position of underwater features. This data is then used to create nautical charts, which are essential for ships and boats to navigate safely.
Here are some additional details about the basic techniques of hydrographic surveying: Sounding: Sounding is a relatively simple technique, but it can be very effective in shallow waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bathymetric Studies</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/bathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/bathy/</guid>
      <description>What are Bathymetric Studies? Bathymetric studies are essential for understanding the oceans. They provide information about the depth and shape of the seafloor, which can be used to map ocean currents, identify potential hazards, and understand the distribution of marine life.
Methods of Bathymetric Studies Two common methods of bathymetric data collection are precision depth recorders (PDRs) and side-scan sonar (SOPAR).
Precision depth recorders (PDRs) are acoustic devices that measure the depth of the seafloor by sending out a sound pulse and recording the time it takes for the echo to return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broker&#39;s responsibility to the principal</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokerespons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokerespons/</guid>
      <description>A broker has a number of responsibilities to their principal, including: Loyalty: The broker must act in the best interests of their principal at all times. This means avoiding any conflicts of interest and not disclosing confidential information to third parties. Skill and care: The broker must exercise a reasonable degree of skill and care in carrying out their duties. This includes keeping up to date with market developments and providing accurate information to their principal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Circulars for Commercial shipping</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/cargocirc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/cargocirc/</guid>
      <description>What are Cargo Circulars? Commercial shipping cargo circulars are documents issued by shipping companies, freight forwarders, and other maritime industry stakeholders to provide information and guidance on a variety of topics related to cargo shipping. These circulars can cover a wide range of topics, such as:
New or updated shipping regulations Changes to freight rates or shipping services Port congestion or disruptions Dangerous goods shipping requirements Cargo insurance and claims procedures New technologies and trends in cargo shipping Cargo circulars are an important source of information for businesses and individuals involved in the shipping of goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charter party disputes</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chrtrdispute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chrtrdispute/</guid>
      <description>Charter party disputes are disagreements between charterers and shipowners over the terms of a charter party. Charter parties are complex legal documents, and it is not uncommon for disputes to arise over their interpretation.
Some of the most common charter party disputes include:
Freight rate disputes: Freight rate disputes arise when the charterer and shipowner disagree on the freight rate that is payable under the charter party. This can happen for a variety of reasons, such as a change in market conditions, a dispute over the quantity of cargo transported, or a disagreement over the distance traveled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-Tidal Charts</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/cotidal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/cotidal/</guid>
      <description>Co-tidal charts Co- Tidal Charts are a valuable tool for mariners, fishermen, coastal engineers, and climate scientists. They provide information about the tidal wave propagation, which is the movement of the tides through the oceans. This information can be used to predict the times and heights of the high and low tides, as well as the direction of the tidal currents.
Co-tidal charts are created using a variety of data, including tide gauge data, satellite data, and computer models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commission on Limits of the Continental Shelf</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/clcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/clcs/</guid>
      <description>What is CLCS and describe it&amp;rsquo;s functions. The Commission on the Limits of the Continental Shelf (CLCS) is a 21-member body of experts established under the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) to consider submissions from coastal states on the outer limits of their continental shelf beyond 200 nautical miles from their baselines.
The CLCS&amp;rsquo;s work is important because the continental shelf is a valuable resource that can contain oil, gas, and other minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation of resources</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/conserv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/conserv/</guid>
      <description>What is Conservation of Marine Resources Conservation of marine resources is the protection and preservation of ecosystems in oceans and seas through planned management in order to prevent the over-exploitation of these marine resources.
There are a number of different ways to conserve marine resources, including: Marine protected areas (MPAs): MPAs are areas of the ocean where certain activities, such as fishing or mining, are restricted or prohibited. MPAs can help to protect marine ecosystems and the species that live in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control in hydrographic surveying</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/control/</guid>
      <description>Control in hydrographic surveying is the process of establishing a network of known horizontal and vertical positions that is used to reference all other survey measurements. Control is essential for ensuring the accuracy and reliability of hydrographic surveys.
There are two main types of control in hydrographic surveying: horizontal control and vertical control.
Horizontal control establishes the horizontal position of survey points. It is typically established using a network of geodetic survey markers, such as triangulation stations and GPS reference points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclonic Storms</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/cyclones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/cyclones/</guid>
      <description>What is a Cyclonic storm?
Cyclonic storms, also known as tropical cyclones, hurricanes, and typhoons, are rotating wind systems that form over warm ocean waters. They are characterized by a central region of low atmospheric pressure and strong winds that rotate in a counterclockwise direction in the Northern Hemisphere and clockwise direction in the Southern Hemisphere.
How is a cyclonic storm formed?
The formation of cyclonic storms is a complex process that requires a number of factors to come together, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deductions from Freight</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/deduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/deduct/</guid>
      <description>Any deductions from freight should be made only if there is express agreement in the charterparty, for example, Address Commission or Brokerage Commission, Cash to Master etc.
Under English law there is a rule known as equitable set-off where claims may be deducted from monies being under a contract, this rule does not apply to freight and was firmly established in The Aries (1977). The Aries (1977) case covered a cargo of oil, where freight was payable on the intaken quantity on delivery of the cargo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demersal and Pelagic fishing</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/demerpelag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/demerpelag/</guid>
      <description>Demersal and pelagic fishing are two different types of fishing that target different types of fish in different habitats.
Demersal fishing is the fishing of fish that live on or near the bottom of the ocean. These fish are also known as groundfish. Demersal fish are typically caught using bottom trawls, gillnets, and longlines.Some examples of demersal fish include cod, haddock, flounder, sole, and shrimp.
Pelagic fishing is the fishing of fish that live in the open ocean, away from the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desalination processes</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/desalination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/desalination/</guid>
      <description>There are two main types of desalination processes: thermal and membrane. Thermal desalination processes use heat to evaporate seawater, leaving behind the salt and impurities. The most common thermal desalination processes are:
Multi-stage flash distillation (MSF): MSF is the most mature thermal desalination technology. In MSF, seawater is heated to a high temperature and then flashed into steam. The steam is then condensed to produce fresh water.
Multiple-effect distillation (MED): MED is similar to MSF, but it uses a series of chambers with different temperatures and pressures to improve efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between dry cargo and tanker chartering</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/diffdcrgotnkchrtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/diffdcrgotnkchrtr/</guid>
      <description>Differences between dry cargo and tanker chartering:
Type of cargo: Dry cargo chartering involves the carriage of dry cargo, such as iron ore, coal, and grain. Tanker chartering involves the carriage of liquid cargo, such as oil and chemicals. Ship type: Dry cargo chartering typically involves the use of bulk carriers, general cargo ships, and container ships. Tanker chartering typically involves the use of crude oil tankers, product tankers, and chemical tankers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution of Salinity, Temperature and Density of Water</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/watermass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/watermass/</guid>
      <description>The distribution of salinity, temperature, and density of water masses is determined by a number of factors, including: Latitude: Salinity and temperature generally decrease with increasing latitude. This is because the sun&amp;rsquo;s rays are more intense at the equator, which causes the water to evaporate and leave behind the salt. The evaporated water then travels to the poles, where it condenses and falls as precipitation. This precipitation dilutes the salinity of the ocean water and lowers its temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dry Cargo chartering</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/dcargochrtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/dcargochrtr/</guid>
      <description>Dry cargo chartering is the process of negotiating and agreeing to a contract for the carriage of dry cargo by sea. Dry cargo charter parties can be complex and vary depending on the specific terms agreed upon by the charterer and shipowner. However, there are some common features of dry cargo charter parties.
Types of dry cargo charter parties
There are two main types of dry cargo charter parties: voyage charter parties and time charter parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth&#39;s status and Earth&#39;s interior age</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/earthintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/earthintro/</guid>
      <description>The Earth Earth is a terrestrial planet in the Solar System, the third planet from the Sun. It is the only astronomical object known to support life. Earth is a sphere with a slightly flattened diameter of about 12,742 kilometers (7,918 mi). Its mass is about 5.972 × 10^24 kilograms (1.317 × 10^25 lb). Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere is composed of 78.09% nitrogen, 20.95% oxygen, 0.93% argon, 0.04% carbon dioxide, and small amounts of other gases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Nino and La Nina</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/el-nino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/el-nino/</guid>
      <description>By influencing global temperatures and precipitation, the El Niño/Southern Oscillation (ENSO) significantly impacts Earth’s ecosystems and human societies. El Niño and La Niña are opposite extremes of the ENSO, which refers to cyclical environmental conditions that occur across the Equatorial Pacific Ocean. These changes are due to natural interactions between the ocean and atmosphere. Sea surface temperature, rainfall, air pressure, atmospheric and ocean circulation all influence each other. A satellite image of the Earth showing an abnormally warm area near the equator off the West Coast of South America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishment of Datums</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/datums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/datums/</guid>
      <description>What is a datum? A datum is a reference system that is used to measure distances, elevations, and other geospatial data. Datums are important because they allow us to compare geospatial data from different sources and to create maps and charts that are accurate and consistent.
Types of datums There are two main types of datums: horizontal datums and vertical datums.
Horizontal datums are used to measure distances on a flat surface, such as the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>excepted periods</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/excperiods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/excperiods/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions to Laytime In a voyage charterparty agreement, there are certain situations where laytime may be suspended or not counted. These exceptions to laytime are generally outlined in the charterparty terms and conditions. Some common exceptions to laytime include:
Weather Conditions: Laytime may be suspended or not counted during periods of bad weather, such as heavy rain, storms, or fog, which can disrupt or delay loading and discharging operations. This type of exception is often referred to as Weather Working Days (WWD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraction of Minerals from seabed</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralextraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralextraction/</guid>
      <description>Definition The extraction of minerals from the seabed is a relatively new and developing industry. It involves the retrieval of mineral deposits from the ocean floor at depths of 200 metres /660 feet or more.
There are three main types of mineral deposits that are of interest for seabed mining: polymetallic nodules, seafloor massive sulfides (SMS), and cobalt-rich ferromanganese crusts.
Polymetallic nodules are potato-sized rocks that are found on the deep ocean floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries(CCRF)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/ccrf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/ccrf/</guid>
      <description>What is CCRF? The FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries (CCRF) is a voluntary international instrument that sets out principles and standards for the conservation, management and development of living aquatic resources. It was adopted by the FAO Conference in 1995 and has since been endorsed by over 180 countries.
The CCRF is based on the following principles: The precautionary approach: States should act with caution when taking decisions that could have a negative impact on living aquatic resources, even if there is no scientific certainty that such an impact will occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial elements of charter parties (freight per ton. or lump sum)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/finelements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/finelements/</guid>
      <description>The financial elements of charter parties can be complex and vary depending on the type of charter party and the specific terms agreed upon between the shipper and carrier. However, there are two main types of freight payments that are typically used in charter parties: freight per ton and lump sum.
Freight per ton is the most common type of freight payment used in charter parties, particularly for dry bulk and tanker shipments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Types</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishtyp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishtyp/</guid>
      <description>Fish Types Types of fish marine resources can be classified according to their body type, habitat, or commercial value.
According to body type: Bony fish: This is the largest group of fish, accounting for over 95% of all fish species. They have a skeleton made of bone and a swim bladder that helps them control their buoyancy. Examples of bony fish include tuna, cod, salmon, and herring.
Cartilaginous fish: This group includes sharks, rays, and skates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fishing Factory Vessels</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfactory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfactory/</guid>
      <description>What are Fishing Factory Vessels? Fishing factory vessels (FFVs) are large ocean-going ships that are equipped to catch, process, and store fish. They are also known as fish processing vessels, mother ships, or floating factories. FFVs are typically used to fish in remote waters, where they can stay at sea for months at a time.
FFVs are highly efficient fishing vessels that can catch and process large quantities of fish. They are also equipped with sophisticated freezing and storage facilities, which allow them to maintain the freshness of the fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General characteristics of the seas</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seas/</guid>
      <description>General characteristics of the seas Seas are smaller bodies of water than oceans and are usually partially enclosed by land. Seas are typically shallower than oceans, with an average depth of about 650 feet (200 meters). The salinity of seas can vary depending on the location, but it is generally lower than the salinity of oceans. Seas are home to a variety of marine life, including fish, shellfish, and seabirds. Bottom topography of the seas</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Idea of Drilling</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/drilling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/drilling/</guid>
      <description>Drilling for oil and gas in marine environments is a complex and challenging process. It involves the construction of offshore drilling rigs or platforms, the use of specialized equipment and tools, and the implementation of strict safety and environmental protection measures.
General idea on drilling The first step in drilling for marine resources is to identify a potential drilling location. This is done using a variety of methods, including seismic surveys and geological studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genesis of rocks, types of rocks,distribution of rocks in the continents and oceans</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/rocks/</guid>
      <description>Discuss Genesis of Rocks Rocks are formed through a variety of geological processes, which can be broadly classified into three main types:
Igneous rocks are formed from the cooling and solidification of molten magma or lava. Magma is generated within the Earth&amp;rsquo;s mantle, and can rise to the surface and erupt as lava, or cool and solidify underground. Igneous rocks are typically classified based on their composition and texture. Some common examples of igneous rocks include granite, basalt, and obsidian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographical location of fishing grounds</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishgrnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishgrnd/</guid>
      <description>What are fishing grounds? Fishing grounds are areas of the ocean where fish are abundant and can be caught commercially. They are typically located in areas where there is a lot of food for fish, such as near continental shelves, upwelling areas, and around coral reefs.
The geographical location of fishing grounds varies depending on the type of fish being targeted. For example, tuna fishing grounds are typically located in tropical and subtropical waters, while cod fishing grounds are typically located in colder waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Energy from Sea</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/power/energyfmsea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/power/energyfmsea/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of different ways to harness energy from the sea, including: Tidal energy: Tidal energy is generated by the movement of the tides. Tidal turbines can be installed in areas where the tides are strong to generate electricity.
Wave energy: Wave energy is generated by the movement of ocean waves. Wave energy converters can be installed on the seabed or on the surface of the ocean to generate electricity from the waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat Budget of the Oceans</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/heatbudget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/heatbudget/</guid>
      <description>What is the heat budget of the oceans? The heat budget of the oceans is a measure of the heat that the oceans absorb and release. It is an important part of the global climate system, as the oceans play a major role in regulating the Earth&amp;rsquo;s temperature.
##The main components of the ocean heat budget are:
Shortwave radiation: This is the energy from the sun that reaches the ocean surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Calculations</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/hirecalc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/hirecalc/</guid>
      <description>Hire calculations in commercial shipping
Hire calculations in commercial shipping are used to determine the amount of money that a charterer will pay to a shipowner for the use of a ship for a specific period of time. There are two main types of hire calculations: voyage hire and time charter hire.
Voyage hire is calculated based on the amount of cargo that is transported and the distance that it is traveled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Satellite Meteorology</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/satmethistory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/satmethistory/</guid>
      <description>Development of Satellite Meteorology The historical development of satellite meteorology can be traced back to the early days of the space race between the United States and the Soviet Union. In 1957, the Soviet Union launched Sputnik 1, the first artificial satellite to orbit Earth. Sputnik 1 provided the first space views of our planet&amp;rsquo;s surface and atmosphere, and its success spurred the development of meteorological satellites.
The first weather satellite, Vanguard 2, was launched by the United States in 1959.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/ice/</guid>
      <description>Ice formation: Ice forms when water cools below its freezing point (0 degrees Celsius or 32 degrees Fahrenheit). However, water can remain liquid below its freezing point if it is pure and undisturbed. This is because water molecules are constantly moving and colliding with each other. When a water molecule collides with another water molecule, it can transfer some of its energy to the other molecule. This energy transfer can prevent the water molecules from slowing down enough to form ice crystals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Satellite Meteorology Programme (ISMP)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/ismp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/ismp/</guid>
      <description>What is ISMP? The Indian Satellite Meteorology Programme (ISMP) is a joint initiative of the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) and the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO). The ISMP was established in the early 1970s, and it has played a vital role in the development of India&amp;rsquo;s meteorological capabilities.
What are the key objectives of ISMP? The ISMP&amp;rsquo;s primary objective is to provide IMD with the satellite data needed to improve weather forecasting and to monitor climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indications and firm offers</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/indicatoroffers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/indicatoroffers/</guid>
      <description>Commercial shipping indications and firm offers are two essential tools used in the shipping industry. Indications are non-binding communications that provide information about a potential shipping arrangement and are used to initiate negotiations between a shipper and a carrier. Firm offers, on the other hand, are binding communications that offer a specific shipping arrangement at a specific price and are used to finalize shipping arrangements once negotiations have been completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Seabed Authority</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/isa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/isa/</guid>
      <description>T## he International Seabed Authority (ISA):
is an intergovernmental organization of 167 member states and the European Union established under the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) and its 1994 Agreement on Implementation. The ISA is headquartered in Kingston, Jamaica.
The ISA&amp;rsquo;s dual mission is to: Organize and control mining activities in the international seabed, which is considered the &amp;ldquo;common heritage of mankind.&amp;rdquo; Protect the marine environment from potential harm caused by mining activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laytime Calculation</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/laytimecalc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/laytimecalc/</guid>
      <description>Laytime Calculation Laytime is the period of time within which the loading or discharging operation is required to be successfully completed according to the charter-party. Laytime is at the charterer’s free disposal in other words laytime is already included in the freight calculations. If laytime period is exceeded, charterer will have to pay remuneration to the shipowner in the form of demurrage or damages for detention.
Obviously, it is for the benefit of the charterer’s interest for the laytime period to be as broad as possible in order to take into account for unexpected events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine Fish Farming</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/marfish/fishfarm/</guid>
      <description>What is Marine Fish farming? Marine fish farming is the cultivation of marine fish in enclosed areas, such as coastal waters, offshore cages, or tanks. It is a rapidly growing industry, as it offers a number of advantages over wild fishing, including:
Sustainability: Marine fish farming can help to reduce the pressure on wild fish populations. This is because farmed fish are raised in controlled environments, where they are less susceptible to overfishing and other stressors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean Sea Level</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/msl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/msl/</guid>
      <description>Mean sea level (MSL) is the average height of the sea&amp;rsquo;s surface over a period of time, typically 19 years. It is a reference point for measuring elevations and changes in sea level.
MSL is determined by averaging hourly tide measurements over the period of time. This average is then adjusted for the effects of non-tidal factors, such as atmospheric pressure and wind.
There are two main methods for determining MSL: Tide gauges: Tide gauges are instruments that measure the height of the sea surface at a specific location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorological Observation Systems</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/metobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/metobs/</guid>
      <description>Synoptic weather observations Synoptic weather observations are observations of the atmosphere that are made at regular intervals, typically every three or six hours, at a global network of weather stations. These observations are used by meteorologists to create weather maps and forecasts.
Synoptic weather observations typically include the following elements:
Temperature: The air temperature at the time of the observation. Dew point: The temperature at which the air would become saturated with water vapor and condensation would occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods of extracting minerals from seawater</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralsextract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/mineralsextract/</guid>
      <description>Methods of extraction of Minerals There are a number of methods of extracting minerals from seawater. Some of the most common methods include:
Solar evaporation: This is the oldest and simplest method of extracting minerals from seawater. It involves using the sun&amp;rsquo;s heat to evaporate seawater, leaving behind the mineral salts. Solar evaporation is typically used to extract salt from seawater, but it can also be used to extract other minerals, such as magnesium and potassium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Tidal Theory</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/moderntide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/moderntide/</guid>
      <description>Modern tidal theory is based on the dynamic theory of tides, which was developed in the 18th and 19th centuries. The dynamic theory of tides takes into account the effects of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotation, the shape of the ocean basins, and the friction between the water and the seabed.
Modern tidal theory is used to predict the tides at any location on Earth. To do this, scientists use complex computer models that take into account all of the factors that influence the tides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohole Project</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/mohole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/mohole/</guid>
      <description>What is the Mohole Project? The Mohole project was an attempt to drill through the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust and mantle to the Mohorovičić discontinuity, also known as the Moho. The Moho is a boundary between the crust and mantle, and it is located at a depth of about 6 miles (10 kilometers) beneath the ocean floor.
The project was conceived in the 1950s by scientists who believed that drilling to the Moho would provide valuable insights into the structure and composition of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Governance</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/defoceangov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/defoceangov/</guid>
      <description>What is Ocean Governance? Ocean governance is the process by which the world&amp;rsquo;s oceans are managed and used. It encompasses a wide range of actors and institutions, including governments, international organizations, businesses, civil society groups, and individuals.
Ocean governance is important because the oceans play a vital role in the global economy and environment. They provide food, jobs, transportation, and recreation. They also regulate the climate, produce oxygen, and support a wide range of biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical properties of seawater, light penetration and colour of the sea</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seawater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seawater/</guid>
      <description>Composition of seawater Seawater is a complex mixture of water, salts, and other dissolved substances. It has a number of unique physical properties, including:
Salinity: Salinity is a measure of the amount of dissolved salts in seawater. It is typically expressed in parts per thousand (ppt). The average salinity of seawater is about 35 ppt, but it can vary depending on location and depth.
Density: Density is a measure of how much mass is contained in a given volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipe Laying including use of Submersibles</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/pipelay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/pipelay/</guid>
      <description>Definition: Pipe laying is the process of installing pipelines on the seabed or underground. Submersibles are vehicles that can operate underwater. They are used in a variety of tasks, including pipe laying.
Types of submersibles used in pipe laying There are two main types of submersibles used in pipe laying:
Remotely operated vehicles (ROVs): ROVs are unmanned submersibles that are controlled from a surface vessel. They are typically used for tasks such as inspection, maintenance, and repair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Position Fixing using short range high accuracy radio signals</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/posfix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/posfix/</guid>
      <description>Short-range high accuracy radio signals can be used for hydrographic survey position fixing in a number of ways.
One common method is to use a differential global positioning system (DGPS). DGPS works by using a network of ground-based reference stations to correct the errors in GPS signals. This can improve the accuracy of GPS positioning to a few centimeters.
Another method of using short-range high accuracy radio signals for hydrographic survey position fixing is to use a real-time kinematic (RTK) GPS system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedure for negotiation</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/negotiate/</guid>
      <description>The negotiation procedure for ship brokers typically involves the following steps: The charterer provides the ship broker with their requirements: This includes the type of ship required, the cargo to be transported, the loading and discharging ports, and the desired charter period. The ship broker identifies and sources suitable ships: The ship broker will use their network of contacts to identify and source ships that meet the charterer&amp;rsquo;s requirements. The ship broker negotiates the charter contract on behalf of the charterer: The ship broker will negotiate the charter contract with the shipowner on behalf of the charterer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative estimation of sea surface temperature (SST)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/qestsst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/qestsst/</guid>
      <description>Quantitative estimation of sea surface temperature (SST) can be done using a variety of methods, including: Satellite remote sensing: Satellites equipped with infrared and microwave sensors can be used to measure SST from space. These sensors measure the amount of infrared and microwave radiation emitted by the sea surface, which is related to its temperature.
In situ measurements: In situ measurements of SST can be made using a variety of sensors, such as buoys, ships, and aircraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remedies for broker in case of breach of conditions</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokeremedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokeremedy/</guid>
      <description>If a ship broker breaches any of their conditions, the principal may have a number of remedies available to them, including: Termination of the agency agreement: The principal may terminate the agency agreement, which will end the broker&amp;rsquo;s authority to act on their behalf.
Damages: The principal may sue the broker for damages for any losses they have suffered as a result of the breach.
Injunctive relief: The principal may seek an injunction to prevent the broker from continuing to breach their conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote sensing techniques</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/rsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/rsense/</guid>
      <description>What are Remote sensing Techniques used for meteorology? Remote sensing techniques are used in meteorology to measure and monitor atmospheric conditions from a distance. This is done by detecting and measuring electromagnetic radiation emitted or reflected by the atmosphere and its constituents, such as clouds, aerosols, and precipitation.
Different types of remote sensing techniques are used in meteorology, including:
Satellite imagery: Satellites provide global coverage of the atmosphere, allowing meteorologists to track weather systems and monitor climate trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand and Gravel Dredging</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/sandgrvldredge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/sandgrvldredge/</guid>
      <description>Definition Sand and gravel dredging is the process of extracting sand and gravel from the bottom of rivers, lakes, oceans, and other bodies of water. It is a common method of obtaining these materials, which are used in a variety of construction and industrial applications.
There are two main types of sand and gravel dredging: Hydraulic dredging: This type of dredging uses a pump to suck up sand and gravel from the bottom of the water body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seabed Sampling</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seabedsample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seabedsample/</guid>
      <description>Definition Seabed sampling is the process of collecting sediment and rock samples from the ocean floor.
Seabed samples are collected for a variety of purposes, including: To study the composition and distribution of seabed sediments: This information can be used to understand the geological history of an area, as well as to identify potential resources, such as minerals and oil and gas.
To monitor the environmental health of the ocean: Seabed samples can be analyzed for contaminants, such as heavy metals and pesticides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seismic and Sonar Profiling</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seismicsonarprofiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/minerals/seismicsonarprofiling/</guid>
      <description>Definition Seismic and sonar profiling are two types of geophysical surveying techniques that are used to image the subsurface of the Earth.
Functioning Seismic profiling uses sound waves to generate images of the subsurface. Seismic waves are generated by a source, such as an explosive charge or a vibroseis truck, and they travel through the subsurface at different speeds depending on the density and elasticity of the rocks they encounter. The waves are reflected back to the surface by different layers of rock, and these reflections are detected by receivers, such as geophones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Facilities</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/storage/</guid>
      <description>There are a variety of storage facilities used for oil and gas, depending on the type of product being stored and the location. Some of the most common types of storage facilities include:
Above-ground tanks: Above-ground tanks are the most common type of storage tank for oil and gas. They can be made of steel, concrete, or fiberglass, and come in a variety of sizes and shapes. Above-ground tanks are typically used for storing crude oil, refined petroleum products, and natural gas liquids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submarine Atlas</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/satlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/satlas/</guid>
      <description>What is a Submarine Atlas? A submarine atlas is a collection of maps and charts that show the features of the ocean floor. Submarine atlases are used for a variety of purposes, including navigation, scientific research, and resource management.
The following are some of the steps involved in preparing a submarine atlas:
Collect data: The first step is to collect data about the ocean floor. This data can be collected using a variety of methods, including bathymetric surveys, acoustic imaging, and satellite remote sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surface Ocean Currents</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/oceancurr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/oceancurr/</guid>
      <description>Surface ocean currents are driven by a combination of factors, including: Wind: Wind is the primary driving force of surface ocean currents. As wind blows across the ocean, it drags the surface water along with it. The direction of a surface current is generally determined by the direction of the prevailing wind.
Coriolis effect: The Coriolis effect is a deflection of moving objects caused by the Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotation. In the Northern Hemisphere, the Coriolis effect deflects moving objects to the right, and in the Southern Hemisphere, it deflects them to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Development</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/sdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/sdev/</guid>
      <description>Marine sustainable development is the management and use of marine resources in a way that meets the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs. It is essential to ensure that the oceans remain healthy and productive, and that the benefits of marine resources are shared equitably.
There are many different aspects of marine sustainable development, including:
Sustainable fisheries: Fisheries management that ensures that fish stocks are harvested at a sustainable rate, and that fishing practices do not harm the marine environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synoptic cloud patterns and their interpretation.</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/synclouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/synclouds/</guid>
      <description>What are Synoptic cloud patterns? Synoptic cloud patterns are large-scale cloud formations that are associated with specific weather systems. Meteorologists use synoptic cloud patterns to identify and track these weather systems, and to forecast future weather conditions.
Some of the most common synoptic cloud patterns include: Cirrus clouds: Cirrus clouds are thin, wispy clouds that are high in the atmosphere. They are often associated with fair weather, but they can also be a sign of approaching bad weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanker Chartering</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/tankercharter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/tankercharter/</guid>
      <description>Commercial shipping tanker chartering is the process of hiring a tanker ship to transport oil or other liquid cargo. Tanker chartering can be complex and involves a number of factors, including the type of cargo, the size of the ship, the voyage route, and the current market conditions.
Types of tanker charter parties There are two main types of tanker charter parties: voyage charter parties and time charter parties.
Voyage charter parties: Voyage charter parties are agreements for the carriage of a specific quantity of cargo from one port to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Baltic Exchange</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/baltic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/baltic/</guid>
      <description>The Baltic Exchange is a membership organisation for the maritime industry, and freight market information provider for the trading and settlement of physical and derivative contracts. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading source of independent maritime market data, and its indices are used as benchmarks for physical and derivative contracts. [Image of Baltic Exchange building, London]
The Baltic Exchange was founded in 1744, and has been based in London since then. It is a not-for-profit organisation, and is owned by its members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal, 1989</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/baselconv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/baselconv/</guid>
      <description>What is it? The Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal, 1989 is an international treaty that aims to protect human health and the environment against the adverse effects of hazardous wastes. It was adopted on 22 March 1989 and entered into force on 5 May 1992. As of October 1, 2023, it has 189 parties.
The Convention covers a wide range of wastes, including toxic, poisonous, explosive, corrosive, flammable, ecotoxic, and infectious wastes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Equilibrium Tide</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/equitide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/equitide/</guid>
      <description>What is the Equilibrium Tide? The equilibrium tide is the hypothetical tide that would be produced by the lunar and solar tidal forces if the Earth were covered with water to such a depth that the response to these forces is instantaneous. In this idealized case, the Earth would be a perfectly spherical water body with no continents or other obstructions. The equilibrium tide would be a standing wave, with two high tides and two low tides per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Chartering Market</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chartermkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chartermkt/</guid>
      <description>The international chartering market is a global marketplace where shipowners and charterers negotiate contracts to transport cargo by sea. The five major chartering centers are London, New York, Hong Kong, Tokyo, and Singapore.
London is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest chartering center, accounting for around 40% of all global chartering activity. It is a leading center for chartering all types of ships, including dry bulk carriers, tankers, container ships, and gas carriers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The plate tectonic model</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/tectonics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/tectonics/</guid>
      <description>What is Plate Tectonic model The plate tectonic model is the unifying theory of Earth science, explaining the global distribution of earthquakes, volcanoes, mountains, and other geological features. It is based on the idea that the Earth&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere (outermost solid layer) is divided into a number of plates that move relative to each other. The plates interact at three types of boundaries: divergent, convergent, and transform.
The plate tectonic model has been widely accepted by the scientific community since the 1960s, but there are still some areas where there is debate or disagreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ship broker</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/broker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/broker/</guid>
      <description>Who is a ship broker? A ship broker is a specialist intermediary who negotiates contracts between shipowners and charterers. Shipowners are the companies that own ships, while charterers are the companies that hire ships to transport cargo.
Ship brokers play an important role in the shipping industry by facilitating the chartering process. They have a deep understanding of the shipping market and can help shipowners and charterers find the best possible deals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory of preparation of Navigational Chart</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/nchart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/hydrosurv/nchart/</guid>
      <description>Navigational charts are essential tools for safe and efficient navigation. They provide mariners with information about the seafloor, surrounding land, and navigational hazards. Navigational charts are also used for a variety of other purposes, such as coastal engineering, marine research, and maritime planning.
The preparation of navigational charts is a complex process that involves the collection, processing, and analysis of a wide variety of data. The goal of chart preparation is to create a depiction of the seafloor and surrounding land that is accurate, reliable, and easy to use for navigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidal power stations</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/power/tidalpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/power/tidalpower/</guid>
      <description>Tidal power stations are a type of renewable energy power station that harnesses the energy of the tides to generate electricity. The tides are caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and the sun on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. Tidal power stations are typically built in coastal areas where the tides are strong.
How tidal power stations work Tidal power stations use turbines to generate electricity from the movement of the tides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidal Streams,currents and their measurement</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/tidstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/tidstream/</guid>
      <description>Tidal streams and currents are both movements of water in the ocean, but they have different causes and characteristics. Tidal streams are caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and sun on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. They are predictable and follow a regular cycle, with the direction and speed of the current changing with the tides. Tidal streams are strongest in coastal areas and estuaries, where the water is confined and the tidal range is high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tide raising forces</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/tideforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/tideforce/</guid>
      <description>Tidal forces are the gravitational forces that cause the tides. They are caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and the sun on the Earth. The moon&amp;rsquo;s gravity has a stronger effect than the sun&amp;rsquo;s gravity because the moon is closer to the Earth.
Tidal forces are differential forces, which means that they pull differently on different parts of the Earth. The part of the Earth that is closest to the moon is pulled more strongly than the part of the Earth that is farthest from the moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Storm Analysis using Satellite Data</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/sattropic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/sattropic/</guid>
      <description>Satellite data is essential for tropical storm analysis. It provides meteorologists with a global view of tropical storms, allowing them to track their movement, intensity, and structure. Satellite data is also used to assess the potential for tropical storms to produce hazardous weather conditions, such as heavy rain, strong winds, and storm surge.
Here are some specific examples of how satellite data is used for tropical storm analysis: To track the movement of tropical storms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Drilling Rigs, Drill Ships and Well head Oroduction Platforms</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/typesofships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/typesofships/</guid>
      <description>Types of Drilling Rigs Land rigs: Land rigs are the most common type of drilling rig, and can be used to drill wells in a variety of locations, including deserts, forests, and mountains.
Drilling barges: Drilling barges are used to drill wells in shallow water, typically less than 300 feet deep.
Jack-up rigs: Jack-up rigs are used to drill wells in water depths of up to 400 feet. They have legs that can be raised or lowered to elevate the rig above the waterline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Terminals</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/terminaltypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/marineres/oilngas/terminaltypes/</guid>
      <description>There are three main types of sea terminals:
General cargo terminals: These terminals handle a variety of types of cargo, including break-bulk cargo (such as machinery and vehicles), neo-bulk cargo (such as grain and forest products), and containerized cargo.
Bulk cargo terminals: These terminals handle bulk cargo, such as coal, grain, iron ore, and oil. Bulk cargo terminals are typically specialized to handle a specific type of cargo.
Passenger terminals: These terminals handle passenger traffic, such as ferries and cruise ships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNFSA</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/unfsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceangov/unfsa/</guid>
      <description>What is UNFSA? The United Nations Agreement on the Conservation and Management of Straddling Fish Stocks and Highly Migratory Fish Stocks (UNFSA) is an international agreement that aims to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of straddling fish stocks and highly migratory fish stocks.
Straddling fish stocks are those that occur both within the exclusive economic zones (EEZs) of coastal states and in the high seas. Highly migratory fish stocks are those that migrate across the EEZs of two or more coastal states or extend into the high seas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unclos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/intconv/unclos/</guid>
      <description>The Law of the Sea for All Nations. The States Parties to this Convention.
Prompted by the desire to settle, in a spirit of mutual understanding and cooperation, all issues relating to the law of the sea and aware of the historic significance of this Convention as an important contribution to the maintenance of peace, justice and progress for all peoples of the world,
Noting that developments since the United Nations Conferences on the Law of the Sea held at Geneva in 1958 and 1960 have accentuated the need for a new and generally acceptable Convention on the law of the sea, Conscious that the problems of ocean space are closely interrelated and need to be considered as a whole,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical profiles of temperature and humidity</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/vertprof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/vertprof/</guid>
      <description>How Vertical profiles of temperature and Humidity can be measured? Vertical profiles of temperature and humidity from satellite pictures can be retrieved using a variety of methods. One common method is to use infrared sounders. Infrared sounders measure the amount of infrared radiation emitted by the atmosphere at different wavelengths. This information can be used to infer the temperature and humidity of the atmosphere at different altitudes.
Another method for retrieving vertical profiles of temperature and humidity from satellite pictures is to use microwave radiometers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual and Infra red Channels</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/vandirchannels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/satmet/vandirchannels/</guid>
      <description>What are Visual and Infra Red Channels in Satellite Meteorology In Satellite Meteorology ,visual and infrared channels are used to detect and measure different atmospheric conditions and phenomena.
Visible channels: Visible channels detect electromagnetic radiation in the visible spectrum, which is the range of wavelengths that can be seen by the human eye. Visible channels are used to image clouds, fog, and other features on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface.
Infrared channels: Infrared channels detect electromagnetic radiation in the infrared spectrum, which is a range of wavelengths that are invisible to the human eye but can be felt as heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Effects</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/wind_effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/meteorology/wind_effects/</guid>
      <description>Divergence What is wind effects divergence? Wind effects divergence refer to the effects of horizontal winds on the divergence of air. Divergence is a measure of how much air is spreading out from a given point. It is calculated as the sum of the changes in the wind speed in the x, y, and z directions. Wind effects divergence can be either positive or negative. Positive divergence means that air is spreading out from a given point, while negative divergence means that air is converging towards a given point.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
