<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geology and Oceanography on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geology and Oceanography on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active geological processes</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/actgeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/actgeo/</guid>
      <description>What are Active Geological processes? Active geological processes are the forces that are constantly shaping and changing the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. These processes can be slow and gradual, like erosion, or they can be sudden and catastrophic, like volcanic eruptions and earthquakes.
Here are some examples of active geological processes: Volcanoes Volcanoes are openings in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust that allow molten rock, ash, and gases to escape. When a volcano erupts, it can release a tremendous amount of energy, causing widespread destruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bathymetric Studies</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/bathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/bathy/</guid>
      <description>What are Bathymetric Studies? Bathymetric studies are essential for understanding the oceans. They provide information about the depth and shape of the seafloor, which can be used to map ocean currents, identify potential hazards, and understand the distribution of marine life.
Methods of Bathymetric Studies Two common methods of bathymetric data collection are precision depth recorders (PDRs) and side-scan sonar (SOPAR).
Precision depth recorders (PDRs) are acoustic devices that measure the depth of the seafloor by sending out a sound pulse and recording the time it takes for the echo to return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution of Salinity, Temperature and Density of Water</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/watermass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/watermass/</guid>
      <description>The distribution of salinity, temperature, and density of water masses is determined by a number of factors, including: Latitude: Salinity and temperature generally decrease with increasing latitude. This is because the sun&amp;rsquo;s rays are more intense at the equator, which causes the water to evaporate and leave behind the salt. The evaporated water then travels to the poles, where it condenses and falls as precipitation. This precipitation dilutes the salinity of the ocean water and lowers its temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth&#39;s status and Earth&#39;s interior age</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/earthintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/earthintro/</guid>
      <description>The Earth Earth is a terrestrial planet in the Solar System, the third planet from the Sun. It is the only astronomical object known to support life. Earth is a sphere with a slightly flattened diameter of about 12,742 kilometers (7,918 mi). Its mass is about 5.972 × 10^24 kilograms (1.317 × 10^25 lb). Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere is composed of 78.09% nitrogen, 20.95% oxygen, 0.93% argon, 0.04% carbon dioxide, and small amounts of other gases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General characteristics of the seas</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seas/</guid>
      <description>General characteristics of the seas Seas are smaller bodies of water than oceans and are usually partially enclosed by land. Seas are typically shallower than oceans, with an average depth of about 650 feet (200 meters). The salinity of seas can vary depending on the location, but it is generally lower than the salinity of oceans. Seas are home to a variety of marine life, including fish, shellfish, and seabirds. Bottom topography of the seas</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genesis of rocks, types of rocks,distribution of rocks in the continents and oceans</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/rocks/</guid>
      <description>Discuss Genesis of Rocks Rocks are formed through a variety of geological processes, which can be broadly classified into three main types:
Igneous rocks are formed from the cooling and solidification of molten magma or lava. Magma is generated within the Earth&amp;rsquo;s mantle, and can rise to the surface and erupt as lava, or cool and solidify underground. Igneous rocks are typically classified based on their composition and texture. Some common examples of igneous rocks include granite, basalt, and obsidian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat Budget of the Oceans</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/heatbudget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/heatbudget/</guid>
      <description>What is the heat budget of the oceans? The heat budget of the oceans is a measure of the heat that the oceans absorb and release. It is an important part of the global climate system, as the oceans play a major role in regulating the Earth&amp;rsquo;s temperature.
##The main components of the ocean heat budget are:
Shortwave radiation: This is the energy from the sun that reaches the ocean surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/ice/</guid>
      <description>Ice formation: Ice forms when water cools below its freezing point (0 degrees Celsius or 32 degrees Fahrenheit). However, water can remain liquid below its freezing point if it is pure and undisturbed. This is because water molecules are constantly moving and colliding with each other. When a water molecule collides with another water molecule, it can transfer some of its energy to the other molecule. This energy transfer can prevent the water molecules from slowing down enough to form ice crystals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohole Project</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/mohole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/mohole/</guid>
      <description>What is the Mohole Project? The Mohole project was an attempt to drill through the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust and mantle to the Mohorovičić discontinuity, also known as the Moho. The Moho is a boundary between the crust and mantle, and it is located at a depth of about 6 miles (10 kilometers) beneath the ocean floor.
The project was conceived in the 1950s by scientists who believed that drilling to the Moho would provide valuable insights into the structure and composition of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical properties of seawater, light penetration and colour of the sea</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seawater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/seawater/</guid>
      <description>Composition of seawater Seawater is a complex mixture of water, salts, and other dissolved substances. It has a number of unique physical properties, including:
Salinity: Salinity is a measure of the amount of dissolved salts in seawater. It is typically expressed in parts per thousand (ppt). The average salinity of seawater is about 35 ppt, but it can vary depending on location and depth.
Density: Density is a measure of how much mass is contained in a given volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submarine Atlas</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/satlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/satlas/</guid>
      <description>What is a Submarine Atlas? A submarine atlas is a collection of maps and charts that show the features of the ocean floor. Submarine atlases are used for a variety of purposes, including navigation, scientific research, and resource management.
The following are some of the steps involved in preparing a submarine atlas:
Collect data: The first step is to collect data about the ocean floor. This data can be collected using a variety of methods, including bathymetric surveys, acoustic imaging, and satellite remote sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surface Ocean Currents</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/oceancurr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/oceancurr/</guid>
      <description>Surface ocean currents are driven by a combination of factors, including: Wind: Wind is the primary driving force of surface ocean currents. As wind blows across the ocean, it drags the surface water along with it. The direction of a surface current is generally determined by the direction of the prevailing wind.
Coriolis effect: The Coriolis effect is a deflection of moving objects caused by the Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotation. In the Northern Hemisphere, the Coriolis effect deflects moving objects to the right, and in the Southern Hemisphere, it deflects them to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The plate tectonic model</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/tectonics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/tectonics/</guid>
      <description>What is Plate Tectonic model The plate tectonic model is the unifying theory of Earth science, explaining the global distribution of earthquakes, volcanoes, mountains, and other geological features. It is based on the idea that the Earth&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere (outermost solid layer) is divided into a number of plates that move relative to each other. The plates interact at three types of boundaries: divergent, convergent, and transform.
The plate tectonic model has been widely accepted by the scientific community since the 1960s, but there are still some areas where there is debate or disagreement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
