<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Commercial Shipping on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Commercial Shipping on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Broker&#39;s responsibility to the principal</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokerespons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokerespons/</guid>
      <description>A broker has a number of responsibilities to their principal, including: Loyalty: The broker must act in the best interests of their principal at all times. This means avoiding any conflicts of interest and not disclosing confidential information to third parties. Skill and care: The broker must exercise a reasonable degree of skill and care in carrying out their duties. This includes keeping up to date with market developments and providing accurate information to their principal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Circulars for Commercial shipping</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/cargocirc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/cargocirc/</guid>
      <description>What are Cargo Circulars? Commercial shipping cargo circulars are documents issued by shipping companies, freight forwarders, and other maritime industry stakeholders to provide information and guidance on a variety of topics related to cargo shipping. These circulars can cover a wide range of topics, such as:
New or updated shipping regulations Changes to freight rates or shipping services Port congestion or disruptions Dangerous goods shipping requirements Cargo insurance and claims procedures New technologies and trends in cargo shipping Cargo circulars are an important source of information for businesses and individuals involved in the shipping of goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charter party disputes</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chrtrdispute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chrtrdispute/</guid>
      <description>Charter party disputes are disagreements between charterers and shipowners over the terms of a charter party. Charter parties are complex legal documents, and it is not uncommon for disputes to arise over their interpretation.
Some of the most common charter party disputes include:
Freight rate disputes: Freight rate disputes arise when the charterer and shipowner disagree on the freight rate that is payable under the charter party. This can happen for a variety of reasons, such as a change in market conditions, a dispute over the quantity of cargo transported, or a disagreement over the distance traveled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deductions from Freight</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/deduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/deduct/</guid>
      <description>Any deductions from freight should be made only if there is express agreement in the charterparty, for example, Address Commission or Brokerage Commission, Cash to Master etc.
Under English law there is a rule known as equitable set-off where claims may be deducted from monies being under a contract, this rule does not apply to freight and was firmly established in The Aries (1977). The Aries (1977) case covered a cargo of oil, where freight was payable on the intaken quantity on delivery of the cargo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between dry cargo and tanker chartering</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/diffdcrgotnkchrtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/diffdcrgotnkchrtr/</guid>
      <description>Differences between dry cargo and tanker chartering:
Type of cargo: Dry cargo chartering involves the carriage of dry cargo, such as iron ore, coal, and grain. Tanker chartering involves the carriage of liquid cargo, such as oil and chemicals. Ship type: Dry cargo chartering typically involves the use of bulk carriers, general cargo ships, and container ships. Tanker chartering typically involves the use of crude oil tankers, product tankers, and chemical tankers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dry Cargo chartering</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/dcargochrtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/dcargochrtr/</guid>
      <description>Dry cargo chartering is the process of negotiating and agreeing to a contract for the carriage of dry cargo by sea. Dry cargo charter parties can be complex and vary depending on the specific terms agreed upon by the charterer and shipowner. However, there are some common features of dry cargo charter parties.
Types of dry cargo charter parties
There are two main types of dry cargo charter parties: voyage charter parties and time charter parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>excepted periods</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/excperiods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/excperiods/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions to Laytime In a voyage charterparty agreement, there are certain situations where laytime may be suspended or not counted. These exceptions to laytime are generally outlined in the charterparty terms and conditions. Some common exceptions to laytime include:
Weather Conditions: Laytime may be suspended or not counted during periods of bad weather, such as heavy rain, storms, or fog, which can disrupt or delay loading and discharging operations. This type of exception is often referred to as Weather Working Days (WWD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial elements of charter parties (freight per ton. or lump sum)</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/finelements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/finelements/</guid>
      <description>The financial elements of charter parties can be complex and vary depending on the type of charter party and the specific terms agreed upon between the shipper and carrier. However, there are two main types of freight payments that are typically used in charter parties: freight per ton and lump sum.
Freight per ton is the most common type of freight payment used in charter parties, particularly for dry bulk and tanker shipments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Calculations</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/hirecalc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/hirecalc/</guid>
      <description>Hire calculations in commercial shipping
Hire calculations in commercial shipping are used to determine the amount of money that a charterer will pay to a shipowner for the use of a ship for a specific period of time. There are two main types of hire calculations: voyage hire and time charter hire.
Voyage hire is calculated based on the amount of cargo that is transported and the distance that it is traveled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indications and firm offers</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/indicatoroffers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/indicatoroffers/</guid>
      <description>Commercial shipping indications and firm offers are two essential tools used in the shipping industry. Indications are non-binding communications that provide information about a potential shipping arrangement and are used to initiate negotiations between a shipper and a carrier. Firm offers, on the other hand, are binding communications that offer a specific shipping arrangement at a specific price and are used to finalize shipping arrangements once negotiations have been completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laytime Calculation</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/laytimecalc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/laytimecalc/</guid>
      <description>Laytime Calculation Laytime is the period of time within which the loading or discharging operation is required to be successfully completed according to the charter-party. Laytime is at the charterer’s free disposal in other words laytime is already included in the freight calculations. If laytime period is exceeded, charterer will have to pay remuneration to the shipowner in the form of demurrage or damages for detention.
Obviously, it is for the benefit of the charterer’s interest for the laytime period to be as broad as possible in order to take into account for unexpected events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedure for negotiation</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/negotiate/</guid>
      <description>The negotiation procedure for ship brokers typically involves the following steps: The charterer provides the ship broker with their requirements: This includes the type of ship required, the cargo to be transported, the loading and discharging ports, and the desired charter period. The ship broker identifies and sources suitable ships: The ship broker will use their network of contacts to identify and source ships that meet the charterer&amp;rsquo;s requirements. The ship broker negotiates the charter contract on behalf of the charterer: The ship broker will negotiate the charter contract with the shipowner on behalf of the charterer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remedies for broker in case of breach of conditions</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokeremedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/brokeremedy/</guid>
      <description>If a ship broker breaches any of their conditions, the principal may have a number of remedies available to them, including: Termination of the agency agreement: The principal may terminate the agency agreement, which will end the broker&amp;rsquo;s authority to act on their behalf.
Damages: The principal may sue the broker for damages for any losses they have suffered as a result of the breach.
Injunctive relief: The principal may seek an injunction to prevent the broker from continuing to breach their conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanker Chartering</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/tankercharter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/tankercharter/</guid>
      <description>Commercial shipping tanker chartering is the process of hiring a tanker ship to transport oil or other liquid cargo. Tanker chartering can be complex and involves a number of factors, including the type of cargo, the size of the ship, the voyage route, and the current market conditions.
Types of tanker charter parties There are two main types of tanker charter parties: voyage charter parties and time charter parties.
Voyage charter parties: Voyage charter parties are agreements for the carriage of a specific quantity of cargo from one port to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Baltic Exchange</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/baltic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/baltic/</guid>
      <description>The Baltic Exchange is a membership organisation for the maritime industry, and freight market information provider for the trading and settlement of physical and derivative contracts. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading source of independent maritime market data, and its indices are used as benchmarks for physical and derivative contracts. [Image of Baltic Exchange building, London]
The Baltic Exchange was founded in 1744, and has been based in London since then. It is a not-for-profit organisation, and is owned by its members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Chartering Market</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chartermkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/chartermkt/</guid>
      <description>The international chartering market is a global marketplace where shipowners and charterers negotiate contracts to transport cargo by sea. The five major chartering centers are London, New York, Hong Kong, Tokyo, and Singapore.
London is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest chartering center, accounting for around 40% of all global chartering activity. It is a leading center for chartering all types of ships, including dry bulk carriers, tankers, container ships, and gas carriers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ship broker</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/broker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cshipmgmt/broker/</guid>
      <description>Who is a ship broker? A ship broker is a specialist intermediary who negotiates contracts between shipowners and charterers. Shipowners are the companies that own ships, while charterers are the companies that hire ships to transport cargo.
Ship brokers play an important role in the shipping industry by facilitating the chartering process. They have a deep understanding of the shipping market and can help shipowners and charterers find the best possible deals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
