<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Knowledge of Tides on Extra Master India</title>
    <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Knowledge of Tides on Extra Master India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modern Tidal Theory</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/moderntide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/moderntide/</guid>
      <description>Modern tidal theory is based on the dynamic theory of tides, which was developed in the 18th and 19th centuries. The dynamic theory of tides takes into account the effects of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotation, the shape of the ocean basins, and the friction between the water and the seabed.
Modern tidal theory is used to predict the tides at any location on Earth. To do this, scientists use complex computer models that take into account all of the factors that influence the tides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Equilibrium Tide</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/equitide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/equitide/</guid>
      <description>What is the Equilibrium Tide? The equilibrium tide is the hypothetical tide that would be produced by the lunar and solar tidal forces if the Earth were covered with water to such a depth that the response to these forces is instantaneous. In this idealized case, the Earth would be a perfectly spherical water body with no continents or other obstructions. The equilibrium tide would be a standing wave, with two high tides and two low tides per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tide raising forces</title>
      <link>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/tideforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techdoc.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/tideforce/</guid>
      <description>Tidal forces are the gravitational forces that cause the tides. They are caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and the sun on the Earth. The moon&amp;rsquo;s gravity has a stronger effect than the sun&amp;rsquo;s gravity because the moon is closer to the Earth.
Tidal forces are differential forces, which means that they pull differently on different parts of the Earth. The part of the Earth that is closest to the moon is pulled more strongly than the part of the Earth that is farthest from the moon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
